so this isn't Mangia Mangia any kind
hundred and fifty to the development of
the faculties in three of Bhavana one on
one occasion best ones living at Canton
gala in a grove of mikela trees then the
Brahmin student who today a pupil of the
brahmand para sarria went to the best
one exchanged greetings with him the
best one then asked him who tada does
the brahman para Santeria teach he
disciples the development of the
faculties he does master Gautama but
will today how does he teach he
disciples the development of the
faculties here master Gautama one does
not see forms with the eye when does not
hear sounds with the ear that is how the
Brahmin Paris Aria teaches his disciples
the development of the faculties the
Buddha says well if that is so
who didn't then a blind man and a deaf
man will develop faculties and so the
winners first eight the brown students
with today said silence just made
depressed without a response there
knowing this the best one addressed the
venerable Ananda and under the Brahmin
Palace Talia teaches he disciples the
development of the faculties in one way
but in the noble ones discipline the
supreme development of the faculties
he's otherwise an under says now's the
time to he asked them to put it to you
complain so there's now an under how is
there the supreme development of the
faculties in the noble ones discipline
here and under when it bhiku and the
party is just because never once
discipline is yeah once appointed on it
yeah noble ones discipline but then he refers
noble ones discipline but then he refers
to a big a big who sees a form with the
I there rises in him what is agreeable
what to say there Rises what he's
disagreeable there Rises what is both
agreeable and disagreeable he
understands thus there hasn't arisen in
me what is the Griebel what is or what
is disagreeable or it is both agreeable
and disagreeable but that is determined
gross or and apparently arisen gross I
don't know just do not subtle
yeah or laude come it is determined
dependently risen
this is peaceful this is a plan this is
equanimity the agreeable that arose the
disagreeable that a vote and both
agreeable and disagreeable that arose
sees in him and equanimity is
established so this is its but you could
be on them
nobody developing new sites that you
haven't seen before you know that when
he was only getting meditation and you
see things that you don't see as in you
actually perceive things that you don't
perceive know you develop meditation you
can derstand the nature of your sites
that's how you go beyond them a nature
Pali word for nature is Dumber
Pali word for things it's Dumber
understanding Dharma means understanding
things this thing is dependently understands
this thing is dependently understands
that it has nothing to do with him this
is dependent a reason it's other work
saying is a reason independent of me so
it's not a reason for me it's other
reason from Nagamani a sense of i am i'm
not its creator a noble disciple in a
disappear another one only need to do is
remind themselves with that
whenever things arise which is exactly
the same yeah something about what you
perceive finding the better perception
it's about understanding the nature of
perception and then but it's agreeable
disagreeable of neither agreeable or
disagreeable T will be a quantum
aesthetic got to it because there is no
engagement with it of any kind
it says he talks speaks about this
second and how none days want it is
cycling higher training one who has
entered upon the way which maybe will
make you think oh no he's a soda pop
he's talking about a soda planning here
yeah
yeah but one who has entered upon the
way so to me it sounds one who is
actually a soda partner who is making
because one can can can have the
perception of another hand again like
well Mullaperiyar Souter describes but
he hasn't fully developed that very
understanding of their perception I say
our perception of not means
understanding the perception that
committee says he perceives Earth with
Regina but then re Osaka he knows he directly
but then re Osaka he knows he directly
knows her he directly knows when he
perceives as in he understood an
introvert he understood it as determined
but he might not now make further effort
to speed up but the one who does make
death who entered upon the way who is
the facing he partaking navona actively
in his efforts that's the next one and
this is he underwent if bhikkhus the
cycling high training Cesar format the I
hears a sound snow so on colonize the
mind object was the mind there rises in
him what is agreeable there was
disagreeable there arises both agreeable
and it's agreeable he is repelled and
disgusted by that by the agreeable that
arose all the disagreeable holder both
all the disagreeable holder both
agreeable in disapproval this is how one
is a disciple and higher training one
who's entered upon the way yeah that's
how you so first you need to see it you
need to mount it you need to see there's
a reason as in as determined not
innovative and that's already peace this
is p.m. that stencil differential
sotapanna from from proteges then you
would not have that peace of any kind
whether it's agreeable disagreeable here
is no independent high ground on which
he can stand peacefully and safely but
this thing was still keep arising for
the duration of his life like the
symptoms of the illness will still keep
resisting so if he wants to get rid of
all of it then he makes it higher
training in high virtue effort whereby
even that peace that he has in regard to
Greenville disagreable he starts
regarding in us no this is old not
wanted this is all determined he
developed this passion toward it that's
when sorry Buddha said you should regard
the pleasure as pain and pain as a
deadly arrow as in like so it's it's
somewhat like pleasure in pain
he's just pain and more pain as in it's
all disagreeable so just to make sure
you've routed the slightest sort of
traces of ignorance there is manifested
to some subtle lust and whatnot and
that's how you become another so you
take that as a blanket attitude they
will then have to result in the manner
for somebody who has the right view
again like taking a broad-spectrum
antibiotics they will have to get rid of
this you cute from the illness you're
done you just need to wait and the body
immune system will eventually make all
the bacteria whatever else is still
flowing around
disappear oh you take the strong
medicine the you know works exactly
right under the right conditions you
make that effort and you completely rid
of any symptoms here
as well but again without a right view
without having developed the Sun of the
mind without having went to the
distension solitude by yourself without
distraction and breaking of the virtue
to arrive at it that's impossible that's
also how sometimes you know people might
struggle to understand from this point
of view you don't seem like an otter had
no way and the difference is exactly in
that there is a tremendous amount of
peace that sort of fun already develops
for being free from illness or in this
case by being a quantum us in regard to
agreeable disagreeable or neutral point
of view yeah that's massive but now from
Alan's point of view even that he can
actually abandon through development a
bit higher training through developing
this passion to vote it yeah it's my
scene you know exactly yeah but and
that's also that's that's how you can
also understand why sometimes so the
panel's would need encouragement because
again people often think oh it's
automatic you ride view Nevada and she
is just like automatic proaches or
something it isn't first of all it's
become a sort of honor in this case
developed attic equanimity in regard to
whatever touches him he does order the
other suit at the dot he doesn't get
struck by the second arrow of suffering
so he doesn't suffer anymore from that
corner Baku equanimity even suffering
arises he doesn't suffer him in
suffering
many people will be content with that
when he saw the palace would be content
with that because it's already a
tremendous amount of freedom and like
from the from the previous standpoint
all the symptoms lingering symptoms
occasional annoyances and so on nothing
nothing nothing like really that's
that's the similar seven grains and
Himalayas that's how little is left
there's nothing that really but was it
but even that seven grain
left so older you're already economist
in regards to pain pleasure in neutral
you should make the effort and develop
this passion to little bit and that's
how you set up on the way here now and
again that's how sometimes they didn't do it
that's how sometimes they didn't do it
sometimes not the finest taste content
with it I mean even van der Laan
delivered by the Buddha with a Buddha
full of cotton over 20 years he's
attendances he was perfectly content to
and it doesn't mean that he was you know
he was quite peaceful most of the tongue
holes only went like sorry put the died
that he was but even that he mighty
blues like his clan faculties might have
kind of go he lost the clarity of it but
well he still couldn't lose is that hard
round of equanimity of safety in all
don't need to do is just when that
phenomenon ceases it's over so he hasn't
been suffering even amidst the
sufferings while protrusion will be
completely destroyed and overwhelmed but
from Adams point of view there is still
a degree to be a cheese you really
practice dead disenchantment
and eager to describe the arahant and
how and under is one a noble one with
developed faculties it's a bit of a
tongue twister see here and underwent a
because he's a form with the I hear the
sound of the year and so on there rises
in him what he's agreeable so he's
arrogant they're rising what it's
agreeable what he's disagreeable in they
rises what his birthday and his squeals
same like for all three so he's not like
oblivious to him as in robotic and then
he says if he should wish may I buy
deceiving the Unruh pulses in the
repulsors your buyers perceiving an
impulsive impulsive if he should wish
male by perceiving their repulsive in
the unreal also few buyers perceiving it
if you develop it that attitude then
agreeable will be seen as disagreeable
and disagreeable will be seen as twice
the disagreeable you know you can
perceive what is disagreeable and
agreeable or the agreeable into
disagreeable as in it's less
disagreeable on account of disagreeable
because you're fully surmounted the
whole domain of the determined that
which is determined as you see its basis
you see itself you see if you see that
then we understand it so yeah if you
wish to look at this such bitter there
that's been why because you've
completely free from it present abiding
yes it went beyond yeah because if he
should wish sure man selfish yeah may I
avoid birth repulsive a ton repulsive
abiding equanimity mindful and fully
aware he abides in equanimity towards
that mindfully for you when they're
repulsive another repulsive it's
basically really be passive and slightly
less to policy
and that's is the supreme development of
the faculties in another one's
disciplined because this is what should
be done for his disciples what should be
done for his disciples out of compassion
by a teacher who seeks the welfare and
has compassion for them that's I've done
for you and under there are these roots
of trees these engines do not deny your
blade collect what else you will regret
it later
yes go there make the effort to
understand the nature of things go there
may be effort to look at your nostrils